Finding Aid for the Allen Sapp Score Collection, circa 1936-1992
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Manuscripts of Titled Works Not Assigned a "W" Number, 1938-1948, II.; Box 27-28 (53 folders)
  - Cold Blows the Wind (folksong arr.), undated (Box 27, Folder 6)
    For SATB chorus, flute, string quartet
    Pencil holograph, annotated, 9 leaves
  - Concerto for Violoncello in B minor, 1940 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    For solo cello, 2 fl., 2 ob., 2 clar., 2 bn., 4 horns, 2 trpt., 3 trbn., harp, timp., perc., strings
    Ink holograph, unfinished, 7 p.
  - des Voix Ouvertes au Soleil, undated (Box 27, Folder 8)
    Pencil holograph, annotated, unfinished, 1 p.
  - Double Fugue in G minor, 1939 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    Pencil holograph, 3 p. Corrections, red ink
  - Exposition, February 14, 1948 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    For unspecified
    Ink holograph, 10 p. Corrections, red pencil. Manuscript has four titled parts: "Exposition," "Exposition II," "Exposition III," and "Exposition IV."
  - Exposition on subject 16 in Gedalge or ‘Massenet is Moanin’, undated (Box 27, Folder 11)
    Ink holograph, 1 p. + 4 measures, unfinished. Corrections, red pencil. Also includes: "Continuation of Massenet" pencil holograph, 2 leaves, comments, red pencil
  - Fantasy for Piano and Strings in C# minor, June 9, 1938–June 27, 1938 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    For piano, 2 violins, violas, 2 cellos
    Ink holograph, 23 p.
  - Fantasy for Orchestra and Piano, undated (Box 27, Folder 13)
    For piano, 2 clar., 2 trpt., trbn., timpani, xylophone, 2 vln., cello
    Pencil holograph, 19 p., annotated, unfinished. Title page dedication: "To The H.S. Orchestra"
  - 15 Canons, December 12, 1940 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    Ink holograph, 3 p. "Music F" listed on Title page.
  - Fugue in A minor for Piano, 1939 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Fugue in A minor for String Trio, 1939 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    Ink holograph, unfinished, 2 p.
  - Fugue in Bb for Piano, 1938 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Fugue in C Major for Piano, 1939 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Fugue in D Major for Piano, 1939 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - undated, undated (Box 27, Folder 20)
    Ink holograph, annotated, 1 p. Fugue, key of D major
  - Fugue in E minor for String Quartet, 1939 (Box 27, Folder 21)
    Pencil holograph, 6 p. (score). Includes parts, 1+ p. each
  - Fugue in E minor for String Quartet, Feb. 25, 1939 (Box 27, Folder 22)
    For String quartet
    Pencil holograph, 4 p.
  - Fugue in F minor for Piano, Feb. 10, 1939 (Box 27, Folder 23)
    Pencil holograph, annotated, 2 p.
  - Fugue on a Subject by Gédalge, May 17, 1948 (Box 27, Folder 24)
    For unspecified SATB instruments
    Ink holograph, 9 p. Corrections, red pencil.
  - Fugue (after #13 Bk. II of the Well Tempered Clavichord) On a Theme by Koechlin, April 17, 1948 (Box 27, Folder 25)
    Folder also includes: "Fugue (After Bach #XIII Bk. II, WTC)," undated pencil holograph, 20" X 13", 2 p.; Related sketches and drafts, 13 p.
  - Gounod Fugue Subject, undated (Box 27, Folder 26)
    For solo keyboard
    Pencil and ink holograph, 2 leaves. Corrections, red pencil.
  - Haverford School Song for Men’s Chorus, undated (Box 27, Folder 27)
    For TTBB chorus
    Ink holograph, annotated, 1 p.
  - Invention in a minor, undated (Box 27, Folder 28)
    Also includes: 2nd version, labeled "Invention," ink manuscript, 1 p.Additional Movements: "Andante" (6/8 meter), ink, 1 p; "Andante" (2/2 meter), ink, 1 p; other sketches
  - Lullaby (no. 78), undated (Box 27, Folder 29)
    Pencil holograph, 2 leaves. Comments in red ink.
  - The Mail Box, undated (Box 27, Folder 30)
    Pencil holograph, 2 leaves; comments in red ink
  - School Fugue on a Subject by Gedalge, undated (Box 27, Folder 31)
    For Unspecified SATB instruments
    Pencil holograph, 4 leaves, annotated; corrections, red ink. Includes sketches and outlines.
  - Sleep Baby Sleep, undated (Box 27, Folder 32)
    Pencil holograph, 2 leaves
  - Subject by Gedalge, undated (Box 27, Folder 33)
    Ink holograph, 2 p., annotated
  - O For a Booke, undated (Box 28, Folder 1)
    For vocal solo, violin, viola
    Pencil holograph, draft, 9 leaves
  - Piano Sonatina, undated (Box 28, Folder 2)
    Ink holograph, annotated, unfinished, 1 p.
  - Sarabande, undated (Box 28, Folder 3)
    For piano and unspecified solo instrument
  - Short Quartet in F minor, March 20, 1939 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    Pencil holograph, annotated, 18 p.
  - Sinfonietta in B minor op. 9, 1938 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    For 2 fl., 2 ob., Eng. Horn, 3 clar., 2 bn., contrabn., 4 horns, 3 trpt., 3 tbn., tuba, timpani, strings, piano
    Ink holograph, annotated, unfinished, 10 p.
  - Small Pieces for Piano, undated (Box 28, Folder 6)
    I. Minuet in F II. Scherzo in D# III. Scherzo in Eb minor IV. Barcarolle V. Mazurka VI. Berceuse VII. Concert Waltz VIII. Impromptu IX. Polonaise X. Melodie XI. Etude XII. Romance XIII. Nocturne XIV. Prelude XV. Poem XVI. March (à la Prokofief)
    Ink holograph, annotated, 71 p.
  - Sonata in B minor for violoncello op. 4, Feb. 5, 1937-March 8, 1937 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    For violoncello, piano
    Ink holograph, annotated, 24 p.
    "Shows talent but requires assiduous study of form and harmonic development – Aa"-- written in caption.
  - Sonata No. 2 in F Major for Cello op. 6, December 13, 1937-May 8, 1938 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    Ink holograph, annotated, 30 p. Includes cello part, ink holograph, annotated, 9 p.
  - Sonata in F# minor for Organ op. 7, undated (Box 28, Folder 9)
    For organ solo
    Ink holograph, unfinished, 3 p. Folder also includes: pencil and ink sketches, 5 p.sketches for "Suite for Organ," Mvt. I, "Prelude." 1 p., pencil Title page only for "Suite for Organ in D minor op. 10." (1938)
  - Stretto on an Exposition by Gedalge (P. 95 of the ‘Traité’), undated (Box 28, Folder 10)
    Ink holograph, 7 p. Comments, red pencil. Includes draft and sketches
  - Suite of Pieces for Piano, Nov. 1, 1937 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    I. Toccata II. Passacaglia III. Interlude IV. Nocturne V. Dance
    Ink manuscript, annotated, 14 p.
  - Three for Two, July 1943 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Three Part Invention, undated (Box 28, Folder 13)
    Pencil holograph, annotated, 2 p
  - 3 Part Invention for 3 Saxophones in C minor, 1938 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    For saxophone trio
    Ink holograph, unfinished, 1 p.
  - Twelve Variations on a Theme of Paganini op. 1, 1936-1937 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    Ink holograph, 24 p.
  - Two Inventions for String Quartet and Woodwind Trio, 1938 (Box 28, Folder 16)
    For string quartet (I), sax trio (II)
    Ink holograph, 7 p.
  - Two Pieces for String Orchestra, Jan. 23-Feb. 4, 1938 (Box 28, Folder 17)
    For 2 vln., vla., 2 cello, bass
    I. Dirge in Eb minor II. Gaudeant Eb major
    Pencil holograph, 10 p. (2nd movement unfinished)
  - Two 3 Part Inventions for Small Chamber Ensembles, 1938 (Box 28, Folder 18)
    For violin, viola, cello (I); 2 clar., bn. (II)
    Ink holograph, 5 p.
  - Violin Pieces, August 4, 1937–May 21, 1938 (Box 28, Folder 19)
    For violin, piano
    Ink holograph, annotated, 21 p.
- Manuscripts of Works Without Titles or Numbers, circa 1938-1954, III.; Box 29 (folder 1-15)
  Dates, when given, are taken from manuscripts or are approximations based on appearance of item, presence of annotations, or accompanying material.
  Arranged in rough chronological order.
  - Ink holograph, 1 p., Feb. 18 (no year given) (Box 29, Folder 1)
    Marked "andante"
  - Pencil manuscript, annotated, 16 p., undated (Box 29, Folder 2)
    For 2 fl., 2 ob., 2 clar., 2 bn., 1 horn, trpt., strings
  - Ink and pencil manuscript, annotated, 5 p., late 1930’s, early 1940’s (Box 29, Folder 3)
    For 2 fl., 2 ob., 2 clar., 2 bn., 2 horns, strings
    Tempo in caption: "Ruhig Bewegt", quarter note=54
  - Pencil manuscript, annotated, 3 p., undated (Box 29, Folder 4)
    Marked "allegro assai"
  - Pencil manuscript, annotated, 13 p., undated (Box 29, Folder 5)
    For 3 fl., 2 ob., Eng. Horn, 2 clar., bass clar., 2 bn., contrabn., 4 horns, 3 tpt., 2 trbn., tuba, strings
    Last movement incomplete.
  - Ink manuscript, annotated, 2 p., late 1930’s, early 1940’s (Box 29, Folder 6)
    For solo vocal, piano
    Vocal part labeled "mock turtle." Text: "Beautiful soup so rich and green, waiting in a hot tureen, who for such dainties would not stoop, soup of the evening, beautiful soup."
  - Pencil holograph, 2 p., early 1950’s (Box 29, Folder 7)
    For solo tenor voice, piano
    Note attached to manuscript: "Song for Aphra Behn play at Kirkland House 1953?? I was a tutor…incidental music to a play of Aphra Behn (title I can’t reconstruct). Restoration comedy, 1680-90". First line of text: "The happy minute's come"
  - Pencil manuscript, annotated, 5 p., undated (Box 29, Folder 8)
    For unspecified solo instrument (tenor clef) and piano
    2 flats, andante, 5/8 meter
  - Pencil and ink manuscript, annotated, 4 p., undated (Box 29, Folder 9)
    1 movement: 4 sharps, allegro molto, 3/4 meter; 2nd movement 5 ftats, "slow," 2/2 meter
  - Pencil manuscript, 3 leaves, undated (Box 29, Folder 10)
    For reduced score, indications for flute, clarinet, oboe, bassoon, horn, trpt., trbn., d. bass
    "Andantino (2’50" = Duration)" in caption
  - Pencil manuscript, draft, 6 leaves, undated (Box 29, Folder 11)
    For flute, oboe, clar., bassoon, horn, 3 trpt., 2 trbn., d. bass.
    "Adagietto, [quarter note]=80", "All Actual Sounds" in caption
  - Pencil manuscript, 8 leaves, undated (Box 29, Folder 12)
    For flute, clarinet, horn, trpt., 2 vln., cello
    "Overture", "Entract I", "Entract II"--Captions.
  - Pencil manuscript, 3 leaves, annotated, incomplete, undated (Box 29, Folder 13)
    For chorus, string quartet
    text by Shakespeare: "How like a winter hath my absence been from thee…" 2 typed pages with Shakespeare text and works by Donne and Eliot included.
  - Pencil manuscript, 2 leaves, undated (Box 29, Folder 14)
    2/2, "Broadly." Includes 4 leaves of sketches
  - Ozalid reproduction, 12 leaves, undated (Box 29, Folder 15)
    For flute, clarinet, harp, string quartet
    Starts with page 25, labeled "II". Movement I not included
- Sketches and Fragmentary Works, circa 1940-1990, IV.; Box 29 (folder 16-54)
  Divided into four general categories: strings (items 17-20); keyboard (21-34); single-staff (35-46); and miscellaneous (47-54). No arrangement at folder level.
  - Pencil manuscript, 5 leaves, undated (Box 29, Folder 16)
    For violin, cello, piano
    Movements II, IV
  - Pencil manuscript, 1 p., undated (Box 29, Folder 17)
    For violin, viola, cello
    Allegro moderato, three sharps
  - Etude: Ink manuscript, 2 p., undated (Box 29, Folder 18)
    Notation for violin part only
  - Pencil manuscript, 1 p., undated (Box 29, Folder 19)
    For mezzo-soprano, string quartet
    Includes 1 page of row forms. Possible relationship to W84, The Bridal Song
  - Pencil manuscript, 2 leaves, undated (Box 29, Folder 20)
    Three short movements: Slowly", Rather more Quickly", Tempo I". Last movement unfinished
  - Ink manuscript, 3 p., undated (Box 29, Folder 21)
    Single staff sketches on 1st page
  - Ink manuscript, 1 p., undated (Box 29, Folder 22)
    Movement III only; 4 sharps, gaily,2/4 meter
  - Ink manuscript, 1 p., undated (Box 29, Folder 23)
    slow,4/4 meter
  - Pencil manuscript, 2 p., undated (Box 29, Folder 24)
    2 sections: 4/4 meter, 1 flat, 1p. 3/4 meter, 4 flats, 1 p.
  - Ink manuscript, 2 p., undated (Box 29, Folder 25)
    fragmentary
  - Pencil manuscript, 18 measures, undated (Box 29, Folder 26)
    Brillante: 2 flats, 2/4 meter
  - Ink manuscript, 19 measures, undated (Box 29, Folder 27)
    2 sharps, 2/4 meter
  - Ink and pencil manuscript, 2 p., undated (Box 29, Folder 28)
    Fragmentary
  - Suite for 2 Pianos: Pencil and ink manuscript, 3 p., sketches only, undated (Box 29, Folder 29)
  - Two Etudes for Piano: Ink and pencil manuscript, draft and sketches, 2 p., unfinished, undated (Box 29, Folder 30)
    Title crossed out on t.p.
  - Two Preludes for Piano: ink holograph, unfinished, 2 p., 1940 (Box 29, Folder 31)
  - Ink manuscript, 1 p., undated (Box 29, Folder 32)
    No key signature, 3/2 meter, andante-allegro-vivace-agitato
  - Pencil manuscript, 1 p., undated (Box 29, Folder 33)
  - Ink manuscript, annotated, 2 p., undated (Box 29, Folder 34)
    For single staff, treble clef.
    1 flat, andante, 5/8 meter, annotated
  - Pencil manuscript, annotated, 3 p., undated (Box 29, Folder 35)
    For single staff marked viola, oboe, flute, trumpet., violin (in order)
  - Ink (2 p.) and pencil (1 p.) manuscript, annotated, undated (Box 29, Folder 36)
    For unspecified; single staff, treble clef
    4 flats, 2/2 meter. 2nd page caption Second Theme. 3rd page caption II Theme
  - Ink holograph, 1 p., December 1, 1939 (Box 29, Folder 37)
    For single staff; treble clef, "Oboe"
    Also includes 2nd version, no caption, ink manuscript, 1 p.
  - Pencil manuscript, 1 p., undated (Box 29, Folder 38)
    Espressivo", 5 flats, 4/4 meter
  - Ink manuscript, 1 p. + 8 measures, undated (Box 29, Folder 39)
    four flats, 2/2 meter
  - Ink manuscript, 56 measures, undated (Box 29, Folder 40)
    no flats or sharps, 2/2 meter
  - Pencil manuscript, 1 p., undated (Box 29, Folder 41)
  - Pencil holograph, 1 p. + 21 measures, undated (Box 29, Folder 42)
    mixed meter and key signatures
  - Ink manuscript, 8 measures, pencil manuscript, 49 measures, undated (Box 29, Folder 43)
  - Ink manuscript, 1 p., undated (Box 29, Folder 44)
    4 flats, 2/2 meter. With: pencil manuscript, 6 p. Pages 5 and 6 contain part from ink manuscript accompanied by keyboard.
  - Pencil manuscript, 1 p., undated (Box 29, Folder 45)
    For single staff, marked: I. Ob. II. Cl. III. Vn. IV. Bsn. V. B. Cl. VI. n VII. Tbn. VIII. Tpt. IX. Fl. X. Fl.
    On other side of page: pencil and ink manuscript, 1 p. 2 treble clefs, 1 bass clef. 3 flats, 4/4 meter. Measure numbers: 155, 160, 165
  - Pencil manuscript, 2 p. + 4 measures, undated (Box 29, Folder 46)
    For unspecified; soprano, alto, tenor, and bass clefs.
    1 sharp, 3/2 meter, fugue
  - Ink manuscript, annotated, 2 leaves, undated (Box 29, Folder 47)
    For SATB chorus, instrumental accompaniment
    1st leaf chorus only. Text: Lord have mercy upon us and incline our hearts to this low." Corrections and comments in red ink. 2nd leaf includes indication of instrumental parts in reduced score: fl., ob., cl., bn., hn ., tpt., tbn., vla., cello.
  - Pencil manuscript, 1 p. + 7 measures, undated (Box 29, Folder 48)
    For unspecified; 2 treble clefs, bass clef
    3 flats, 2/4 meter
  - Pencil manuscript, undated (Box 29, Folder 49)
    For TTBB chorus (1 p. + 5 measures); single staff, treble clef (1 p.)
    text: We were young, they say, we have died, remember us. The young dead soldiers do not speak, nevertheless they are heard in the still houses.
  - Ink manuscript, 2 p., undated (Box 29, Folder 50)
    For keyboard, trumpet
    1942 printed between staves
  - Pencil manuscript, 1 p., undated (Box 29, Folder 51)
    For unspecified; soprano, alto, tenor, bass clefs
    4 sharps, 4/2 meter
  - Pencil manuscript, 1 p., undated (Box 29, Folder 52)
    Reduced score, indications for fl., cl., ob., bn., hn., tpt., strings
  - Miscellaneous pencil and ink fragments, 10 p., undated (Box 29, Folder 53)
    Unspecified
  - Two Elegies for Septet by Hezekiah Fundless: Ink holograph, unfinished, 1 p., 1943 (Box 29, Folder 54)
    For 2 vln., 2 vla., 2 cello, bass
- Row Forms, Matrices, and Outlines, circa 1955-1981, V.; Box 30 (folder 1-10)
  Instrumentation, when given, is taken from any indication found in the outline, and is not intended to be considered complete.
  Arranged roughly in chronological order.
  - lined yellow paper, 8 ½" X 11", 12 p., undated (Box 30, Folder 1)
    Tempos indicated: dotted eighth = 72; eighth = 60; meter indicated: 12/16; 5/8 (10/16); top of each page marked with a letter, beginning with "A" on 1st page, proceeding consecutively to "L" on 12th page; sketches of structural design, with indications for measures and larger groupings. No staff notation
  - Unlined paper (5 p.), graph paper (1 p.), undated (Box 30, Folder 2)
    Row forms, hexachords, and set-class groupings, in letter names and integer notation. No staff notation
  - Blank, lined, and manuscript paper, 26 p. total, undated (Box 30, Folder 3)
    Separated into groups of pages labeled "I", "J", "K", "L"; row forms, letter names; 1+ pages of staff notation; 2 treble clef staves and 2 bass clef staves
  - Yellow legal paper (3 p.), graph paper (1 p.), undated (Box 30, Folder 4)
    Meter and tempo indicated: 3/8, quarter = 54 ("I"), 9/16-2/4-6/16 ("II"), 5/8, eighth = 55 ("III"), 2/4, quarter = 132 ("IV"). Other tempos indicated: quarter = 72; dotted quarter = 72. Graph paper labeled " Fromm | I". Some rhythmic notation, no staff notation
  - Staff paper, 10 ½" X 13", 4 p., undated (Box 30, Folder 5)
    "Schuller" listed at top of 1st page; row forms, staff notation
  - staff paper, 8 ½" X 11", 2 p., undated (Box 30, Folder 6)
    Row forms, staff notation
  - Staff paper, 9 leaves; vellum, 1 p., undated (Box 30, Folder 7)
    Labeled "Raw Patterns 1955-"; row forms for W16, W18, W19, W20, W60, W62, W105, W113, W115, W127
  - Manilla folder and 1 page of lined notebook paper, undated (Box 30, Folder 8)
    Folder labeled "Compositions 1975-76:; paper contains listing of pieces and names, i.e. "for Bayerly" and "the Boldts" associated with them.
  - Graph paper stapled to manilla folders, 2 p., undated (Box 30, Folder 9)
    For piano, horns, marimba, glockenspiel, bells, xylophone, vibraphone, percussion, double basses, tubas, trumpets
    "Black Holes and White Dwarfs"; 12-tone matrix, Greek letters, no staff notation
  - Lined paper, 1 p.; staff paper, 1 p., undated (Box 30, Folder 10)
    Lined paper labeled "String Quartet V" and "Cleveland, September 30, 1981"; outline using Arabic and Roman numerals, 3 stanzas of French text; row forms, staff notation
- Manuscript Books and Exercises, circa 1935-1945, VI.; Box 30 (folder 11-23)
  No defined arrangement imposed.
  - Five 7 X 10 Clarke's Music Tablet manuscript books, late 1930's, early 1940’s (Box 30, Folder 11)
    2 tablets labeled on cover: Allen Sapp, Cheswold Lane, Haverford, PA. 1 tablet labeled Allen Sapp, 28 Gannock Terrace, Lansdowne, PA. 1 tablet with no address information, and 1 tablet with pages torn from binding. Exercises and sketches, chord progressions. Some text notes on harmonic practice, chord resolutions, etc. Corrections in red pencil.
  - Two 9 X 12 spiral bound manuscript books, late 1930's, early 1940's (Box 30, Folder 12)
    Choral and vocal settings. 1 manuscript book labeled on cover: Allen Sapp Jr., Music H. Corrections and comments in red ink and pencil throughout. Contents: A) "No. 94," 1st line of text: "Marching proudly, marching proudly, went our soldiers to fight in battle… " SATB, a cappella, 1 p. B) "No. 94": "Starry banner proudly flying over the city…" SATB, a cappella, 1 p. C) "No. 67": "Have you ever heard an echo clear, listen as we sing and you shall hear… " SATB, a cappella, 1 p D). "67": "In the woods the echos hide, shout and they shout back from every side… " SATB, a cappella, 1 p. E) "110": "Give three long cheers for sailors on the sea… " SATB, a cappella, 3 p. F) "133, Valentines": "In the dark of the winter when cold winds do blow, Saint Valentine's day comes like flowers in the snow… " SATB, a cappella, 2 p. G) "Lady Bird: Sweet little lady bird rest a while… " SATB, a cappella, 6 p. H) "The Country Farmer's Boy": "I would not be a monarch great with a crown upon my head… " SATB, a cappella, 6 p. I) "Cock-a-Doodle-Doo, No. 56": "Cock-a doodle doo, my dame has lost her shoe… " SSA, piano, 5 p. Folder also contains a 2nd version, ink manuscript, 1 p. Other manuscript book labeled on cover: Allen Sapp, 231 Mass. Ave., Arlington. Corrections and comments in blue and black pencil throughout. Contents: A) "CS #100": "Ah, here is the open trolley, come for a ride with me…" SATB, a cappella, 2 p. B) Untitled: "My tongue shall sing, shall sing of they righteousness… " SATB, a cappella, 3 p. C) "#76": "One morning early fragrant was the air… " SATB, a cappella, 3 p. D) "65": "On winter night when starry winds are driving forth the snow… " SATB, a cappella, 5 leaves E) Untitled: "Sing a song, a gay and tuneful song of ships… " SATB, a cappella, 2 leaves F) Untitled: "Quam olim Abraham promi sisti matura…" SATB, a cappella, 3 leaves G) Untitled: "Aye wakin' O! Wakin' aye an eerie, sleep I canna get for thinking on my dearie… " vocal solo, piano, 3 leaves H) "At Early Dawn of Morning": "At early dawn of morning, while yet the sky was grey…" STB, piano, 5 leaves
  - One 8 X 9 manuscript book, undated (Box 30, Folder 13)
    Reduced score, indications for brass, strings, timpani, 14 p; Sketches, 3 p.
  - Pencil holograph, annotated, 12 p., late 1930’s, early 1940’s (Box 30, Folder 14)
    For 2 violins, viola, cello, bass
    Series of exercises with instructions taken from other source, indicated by page numbers in captions. Corrections, red pencil
  - Ink holograph, 1 p., late 1930’s, early 1940’s (Box 30, Folder 15)
    For 2 oboes, bassoon
    Caption "Music F- Midyear" Marked in pencil, bottom: "My Grade B-"
  - Ink and pencil holograph, annotated, 9 p., late 1930’s, early 1940’s (Box 30, Folder 16)
    Unspecified; treble, tenor, alto, bass clefs
    Set of 4 fugues, corrections and comments in red pencil
  - pencil manuscript, 1 p., late 1930’s, early 1940’s (Box 30, Folder 17)
    unspecified, some vocal text
    Marked "Music H" in caption. Text: "Alleluia"
  - Ink holograph, 23 p., late 1930’s, early 1940’s (Box 30, Folder 18)
    Series of numbered exercises. Harmonic analysis included. Corrections, red pencil
  - Ink manuscript, 7 p., late 1930’s, early 1940’s (Box 30, Folder 19)
    Fugue studies, numbered 2 – 8. Four sharps, 3/2 meter
  - Pencil holograph, 12 p., April 23, 1938; March 19 (no year listed) (Box 30, Folder 20)
    Grand staff, some violin and trumpet with keyboard
    Numbered exercises, no corrections or comments
  - Pencil holograph, 4 p., late 1930’s, early 1940’s (Box 30, Folder 21)
    Unspecified, grand staff
    Series of numbered exercises, 8 measures each
  - Pencil holograph, 3 p., late 1930’s, early 1940’s (Box 30, Folder 22)
    "23" in caption. Two 8-measure exercises, with text notes about choral writing. Chorus text: "Come dance in the orchard ‘mid daisies, mid clover, Come dance in the orchard all under the trees" and "Ring round a rosy, clouds go sailing by, Ring round a rosy, as long as we please." Corrections, red pen.
  - Pencil and ink manuscripts, 10 p., late 1930’s, early 1940’s (Box 30, Folder 23)
    Assorted text notes, 1 page of bowing exercises, fragments
- Arrangements, Transcriptions, and Analyses of Other Composer’s Works, circa 1939-1950, VII.; Box 31 (folder 1-6)
  Manuscripts are assumed to be from Sapp’s time as a student at Harvard, from 1939 to the late 1940’s.
  - Arrangements of piano works for orchestra. 15 ink and pencil manuscripts, some corrections in red pen., type="inclusive">undated (Box 31, Folder 1)
    Sonatina for Piano, Chavez; Five Preludes (Op. 74); Barcarolle no. 3, Fauré; Intermezzo in E major, Brahms; Sonata Op. 53; Variations on a Theme of Paganini; Album Leaf, Scriabin; Le Cahier Romand, Honegger; Prelude and Fugue from Concerto, Stravinsky; Serenade in A, Stravinsky; Fugue from Sonata no. 3, Hindemith; Prelude XI, Debussy; Sonata in C major, Beethoven; Sonata in C minor, Beethoven
  - Arrangements of piano works for strings. 3 pencil and ink manuscripts, most works short excerpts, type="inclusive">undated (Box 31, Folder 2)